We are so in luck!
我們走運了
Treeger said we could have all this cool stuff!
房東說這些好東西都可以給我們
Wait right there.
等一下
Oh,no. I'm paddling away.
不行，我要劃走了
Really? We got all this rusty crap for free?
真的？ 這些生蛌漫U圾不要錢？
This and a bunch of bubble wrap. And some of it is not even popped.
還有一堆泡泡棉 有些完全沒擠過
Could we be more white trash?
我們真是白人垃圾
The One with the Cuffs
本集播出：「愛的手銬」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
How desperate am l?
我真是絕望透了
Good thing Chandler's not here. He always wins at this game.
幸好錢德不在，誰也慘不過他
I just told my mom I'd cater her party.
我剛答應幫我媽的宴會辦外燴
-How come? -I need the money.
為什麼？ 因為我需要錢
It'd be a great way to get rid of that last smidgen of self-respect.
而且這樣正好可以拋開 最後一絲自尊
I think this is a good thing.
別這樣，這是好事啊
Mom wouldn't have hired you if you weren't good.
要不是覺得你行，媽不會找你
You don't have to stick up for her. She can't hear you.
你不必替她說話，她聽不到
Do you have any juice?
你們有果汁嗎？
Just pickle.
只有醃黃瓜汁
Funny story. I bumped into Joanna yesterday.
瑞秋，說來好笑 我昨天在路上遇見喬安娜
My boss,Joanna? That must have been awkward.
我的上司喬安娜？一定很尷尬
Actually,she asked me if I wanted a drink.
事實上她找我一起去喝酒
You didn't say yes to that, did you?
你沒有答應吧？
沒有
Hello,Rachel.
瑞秋
Well,not at first.
一開始沒答應
What is she doing here?
她在這裡幹什麼？
Last time you went out with her you said she was a dud!
我不懂 你上次跟她約會時說她很無聊
I judged her too quickly. This time,we took it to the next level.
我太快下定論了 這次我們進展到下一個階段
Last time I almost got fired. You must end it. You must end it now.
我上次差點被炒魷魚 你馬上給我做個了結
It's not an everyday occurrence!
這可不是每天都有的事
Usually I'm in there by myself.
通常我都一個人睡
Promise.
答應我…
-Rachel,aren't you running late? -No
瑞秋，你快遲到了吧？ 沒有啊
-You are if you pick me up a bagel. -Okay.
有，你還要幫我買焙果 好
Promise you will end this now.
錢德，答應我跟她分手
-I promise. I'll end it. -Thank you.
好，我會跟她分手 謝謝
I hope you know what I'm giving up.
不過我的犧牲很大
She's not just the boss in your office. You know what I mean?
她可不只是你的上司，懂嗎？
Sorry. I knew what he meant.
對不起，我懂
How's the hired help?
外燴大廚忙得怎樣？
Doing great. Quiches are coming along.
很順利，乳酪火腿餡餅快好了
What's this? Blue nail polish?
這是什麼？藍色指甲油？
I thought it was cute.
對，我覺得很好看
It's what your grandmother's hands looked like when we found her.
你奶奶死後指甲就是這個顏色
Let me ask you a question.
我問你一個問題
Why did you hire me?
你為什麼找我？
Richard raved about the food at his party...
理查一直說他的派對餐點很棒
...but you were sleeping with him.
但你當時在跟他上床
Then I heard the food at that lesbian wedding was nice.
後來我聽說 那場同志婚禮的菜很好
I assume you didn't sleep with anyone there.
你應該沒跟那些人上床吧
At least that would be something.
起碼很特別
Oh,my God! Did you hear that?
天哪！你聽到了嗎？
She hired me because she thinks I'm good.
她是覺得我很行才找我
I didn't hear that.
我沒聽到這個
She didn't hire me out of pity.
她不是在可憐我
It wasn't so she could pick on me. She actually thinks I'm good.
不是想在朋友面前刁我 她是真的覺得我行
And hey,it's cool if you're a lesbian.
還有，如果你是同志就太酷了
Good afternoon. Are you the decision-maker of the house?
午安，你是這裡的家長嗎？
Do you currently own a set of encyclopedias?
你目前擁有一套百科全書嗎？
No,but try the classifieds. People sell everything in there.
沒有 不過分類廣告上什麼都有
Actually,I'm not buying. I'm selling.
我不是要買，我是要賣
Let me ask you one question.
我問你一個問題
Do your friends ever have a conversation...
你是否曾在朋友們聊天時
...and you just nod along, not sure what they're talking about?
只能跟著點頭 卻搞不懂他們在說什麼？
I'm telling you, it's totally unconstitutional.
告訴你，這根本是違憲 沒錯
I think he deserves a Nobel Prize.
我覺得他應該得諾貝爾獎
才怪
It was like the Algonquin kids' table.
很像阿爾岡京族小孩的桌子
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
抱歉，對不起
You haven't said anything for about two minutes.
你發了大約2分半鐘的呆
Are you at all interested?
你到底有沒有興趣？
Come on in.
有…請進
-That's weird. -What?
怪了 什麼？
Your nails.
你的假指甲
I wore fake ones so my mom wouldn't give me grief about biting them.
我知道，我怕咬指甲被我媽念
I meant,it's weird that you only have nine now.
我是說你現在只有九個指甲
Oh,my God!
天哪
Wait a minute.
等一下
I had them when I put
我之前要烤…
Oh,my God! It's in the quiche!
天哪，在餡餅裡面
-Oh,my God! -Okay,don't panic.
完了！ 好，不要慌
I'll go buy you a new set of nails.
我去幫你買一組新指甲
No one will know, and you'll look great!
沒有人會知道，你還是很美
It's because they're going to eat That's the problem.
你是怕他們會吃到
Honey,don't bite your nails.
女兒，別咬指甲
Please don't freak out.
你別發飆
There's a blue fingernail in one of the quiche cups.
不過某個餡餅裡有一片假指甲
And there's no way to know which one.
而且無從找起
And whoever finds it wins the prize!
找到的人可以中大獎
I'm not freaking out.
我不會發飆
-Why are you laughing? -Now your father owes me $5.
你在笑什麼？ 沒事，你爸輸我5塊錢
You bet I'd lose a nail?
你賭我會掉指甲？
Don't be silly. I just bet that I'd need these.
別傻了 我只是賭我會用上這個
Frozen lasagnas?
冷凍千層面？
You bet that I'd screw up?
你賭我會搞砸？
All that stuff about how I was good
你還說什麼我很行…
No,that was all true.
不，那都是真的
This was just in case you "pulled a Monica."
這只是怕你搞摩妮卡飛機
You promised Dr. Weinberg you'd never use that phrase.
你答應心理醫生不再這麼說
Come on. Have a sense of humor.
拜託，有點幽默感嘛
You're never able to laugh at yourself.
你總是不懂得自嘲
That's right.
是啊
My mom has no faith in me! That's hilarious!
我媽對我沒信心，好好笑喔
I don't get it.
哪裡好笑？
No. I have faith.
不，我對你有信心
No. You have lasagnas!
不，你有的是千層面
The ruined quiches are ready!
毀掉的餡餅好了
-I really don't think we should be doing this. -Okay.
我們不該這麼做 好
It just doesn't feel like we're breaking up.
這種感覺不像是分手
No,we are. I'm sad.
是分手啊，我好傷心喔
好吧
Can you wait till tomorrow? All right.
可以等到明天嗎？好吧
Unbelievable!
真是帥呆了
Thanks.
謝謝
That was my boss. I have to go.
不是，我得去見我的老闆 好
What are you doing?
你幹什麼？
-I'm getting dressed. -Why?
穿衣服 為什麼？
When I walk outside naked, people throw garbage.
光著屁股走在路上會被扔東西
Wait. I want to show you something.
等一下，給你看個東西
What is it?
什麼東西？
Just a little gag gift somebody gave me.
別人送的一個小道具
Put your hands together.
把手合在一起
You're not the boss of me.
你又不是我的老闆
Yeah,you are.
你是
Saucy!
粉辣喔
I'll be back in two minutes.
我馬上回來
You're going to leave me like this?
你要這樣把我掛著？
Knowing you're here waiting for me. I think it's exciting,don't you?
知道你在等我 感覺很令人興奮
If you don't come back soon...
好，但要是你不馬上回來…
...there's pretty much nothing I can do about it!
我也不能怎麼樣
I brought you back a macaroon.
我幫你帶了杏仁餅回來
Great. I'll keep it in my butt with your nose.
很好，我會把它帖在屁股上
That's weird. She locked the door.
奇怪，她把門鎖上了
You know why? She's got the bonus list in there.
你知道為什麼？ 裡面有聖誕獎金名單
I saw her working on it today.
我早上看到她在打
Swear you won't tell.
好，你可別說出去
When Mark left,he gave me a key to her office.
馬克離職時給了我一把鑰匙
You want to see the list?
你想看名單嗎？ 想
How are you?
你好嗎？
Hello,Joanna
喂，喬安娜…
office.
…辦公室
I'm sorry. I'll be a little longer.
對不起，我還要一陣子
-How little? -A couple hours.
多久？ 2個小時，我急死了
This isn't funny. Get back here now!
一點也不好玩，馬上給我回來
-I can't! -Why not?
我沒辦法 為什麼？
I'm in my boss' car.
我在我老闆的車上
-What? -Tunnel!
什麼？ 進隧道了
What?
怎樣？
Rachel,could I see you for a moment?
瑞秋，你進來一下
Okay,here's the situation.
好，現在是這樣
The keys to the cuffs are on the door.
手銬的鑰匙掛在門上
Could you be a doll...
你能不能行行好
...and grab them and scoot on over here and unlock me?
拿了鑰匙衝過來幫我解套？
And on a totally separate subject, that's a lovely pantsuit.
題外話：好漂亮的套裝
You promised you would break up with her.
你答應要跟她分手的
I did break up with her! She just took it really,really well!
我跟她分手啦 只不過她分得很狂野
Jeopardizing my career never entered your mind?
你都沒想過 這樣會破壞我的事業？
It did enter my mind.
我想過啊
But then something happened that made it shoot right out.
但後來的事讓這個念頭飛了
You got yourself into those cuffs, you get yourself out.
你害自己被銬住，就自己脫困
I can't get myself right out of them.
不，我沒辦法自己脫困
You must have me confused with the "Amazing Chandler"!
你把我跟脫逃大師錢德搞混了
Unlock me! She could be gone for hours,and I'm cold and....
幫幫我啦，她可能要去很久 我好冷，而且…
All right! This is it!
錢德！好，夠了
Never see her again.
不准你再見她
Never!
永遠
-Never come in here again. -Fine!
不准再進這個辦公室 好
Give me back my Walkman!
把隨身聽還給我 我…
I never borrowed it.
我沒借過
Then I lost it. Buy me one!
那就是我弄丟了，買一台給我
You got it! Here we go! Come on. This is great!
沒問題，快解開吧，太好了
Does it hurt?
會痛嗎？
No,I always see guys do this when handcuffs are taken off.
我只是看別人都會哀一聲
Hello,sweet pants!
親愛的褲子
Wait! What will you tell Joanna?
慢著！你要怎麼跟喬安娜說？
About what?
說什麼？
She'll see you're gone and know I let you out,and I'll get fired!
她看你走了會知道是我放的 我會被解雇
I'll tell a lie! I'm good at lying!
我會撒謊，我最會撒謊了
I actually did borrow your Walkman!
我的確借了你的隨身聽
She'll know I have a key to her office.
行不通的，她會知道我有鑰匙
I've got to lock you back up.
我得把你銬回去
I don't think so.
你別想
This is much better.
這樣好多了
Here's somebody interesting.
這個人很有意思
What do you know about Van Gogh?
你對梵谷認識多少？
-He cut off his ear. -And?
他割掉自己的耳朵 還有呢？
I'm out.
沒了
He painted that.
這是他畫的
That's pretty nice.
不賴嘛
I thought he cut off his ear because he sucked.
我以為他是罰自己畫不好
-What else you got in there? -Let's see....
還有什麼？ 我看看
-Where does the Pope live? -ln the woods.
教宗住在哪裡？ 森林裡
Wait,that's the joke answer.
等等，那是開玩笑的
Actually,it's Vatican City.
他住在梵蒂岡
Now,what do you know about vulcanized rubber?
你知道什麼是硫化橡膠？ （另義保險套）
Spock's birth control.
節育用品
You need these books.
你需要這套書
This used to be your room?
這裡是你的舊房間？
You must have been in really good shape as a kid.
你小時候一定很健美
I'm such an idiot!
我真是個白癡
I can't believe I thought she could change.
我居然以為她會改變
Who cares what your mom thinks?
誰管你娘怎麼想？
So you "pulled a Monica."
搞摩妮卡飛機又怎樣
I'm glad that's catching on.
這句話還真流行
Why does that have to be a bad thing? Just change what it means.
誰說這一定要是壞話？ 去改變它的意義
Prove your mother wrong.
去證明你媽是錯的
You finish the job,and we'll call that "pulling a Monica."
你把工作順利完成 我們就管它叫搞摩妮卡飛機
What?
什麼？
If a kid gets straight A's, his parents say,"You pulled a Monica."
小孩每一科都拿A， 父母會說 「你搞了摩妮卡飛機」
A fireman saves a baby, and they go,"He pulled a Monica."
消防員救出一個寶寶 大家會說「他搞摩妮卡飛機」
Someone hits a homer,and they say, "That one's out of here."
有人打全壘打，播報員會說 「這是一支紅不讓」
Because some things don't change.
有些事是不會變的
All right. I'll go down there.
好，我要下樓去
I won't serve the lasagna. I'll serve what I make.
我不上千層面 我要上我做的菜
My breasts are really strong.
我的咪咪真有力
I have to get you locked back up. I'm so going to lose my job!
錢德，拜託，我得把你銬回去 我的飯碗快不保了
She's very private about her office!
她很在意辦公室的隱私權
Now I know why!
我總算知道原因了
You're in trouble either way.
你不管怎樣都有麻煩
If she sees me locked to this...
她看見我被銬在櫃子上
...she'll know you were here. You might as well let me go.
就會知道你進來過 你還不如讓我走
-I'll clean your bathroom for a month. -Still won't be clean.
我幫你洗浴室1個月 還是洗不乾淨
All I want is my freedom.
我只要我的自由
-Foot rubs for a month! -Freedom!
揉腳1個月 自由
-I'll put all your photos into albums! -I want my freedom!
把你的相片通通整理好 自由，我要我的自由
Why won't you hear me! Sophie,help me!
你為什麼不聽 蘇菲，救救我
Sophie,sit!
蘇菲，坐下
自由
Would you just calm down?!
請你冷靜好嗎
I'm going to say this for the last time.
我再說最後一次
Would you please just
能不能請你…
There's a lot I didn't know about vomit.
我對嘔吐的瞭解還真少
In a minute.
等一下
So what do you say?
你覺得如何？
You get the whole set of encyclopedias for $1200.
1200元擁有整套百科全書
That works out to just 50 bucks a book.
平均一本才50元
$1200?
1200？
You think I have $1200?
你覺得我有1200嗎？
I'm home during the day...
我大白天窩在家裡
...and I got patio furniture in my living room.
還用涼椅洋傘當傢俱
There's a few things you don't get from book learning.
有些事是書上學不到的
Well,what can you swing?
你能湊出多少？
How about zero down and zero a month for a long,long time?
0頭期款，月付0元如何？
You don't have anything?
你什麼都沒有？
You want to see what I got?
你想看我有什麼？好
I got a baby Tootsie Roll...
我有一個巧克力棒
...a movie stub,keys,a Kleenex...
一張電影票根、鑰匙、面紙
...a rock...
一塊小石頭
...and an army man.
和一個玩具兵
Okay,I get the picture. Thanks for your time.
好，我懂了，耽誤你了
And a fifty.
和一張50元
These must be Chandler's pants.
這一定是錢德的褲子
For $50 you can get one book.
50元可以買一本
What will it be? A? B? C?
你要哪一本？A？B？C？
I'll stick with the V.
我還是買V好了
I want to see how this bad boy turns out.
我想看看結局如何
I will buy and wrap all of your Christmas gifts!
我幫你買和包聖誕禮物
I'll squeeze you fresh orange juice every morning!
我每天早上幫你搾柳橙汁
-With extra pulp? -Yeah.
有果肉？ 有
不要
I've got it!
我知道了
You don't have it.
你才不知道
I have so got it!
我完全知道了
There will be rumors about this. No way to stop it.
這件事會傳出去，擋也擋不住
Sophie,Monica and Phoebe know.
蘇菲知道 摩妮卡、菲比知道
-How do they know? -I called them.
她們怎麼會知道？ 我打給她們了
When they ask me what I saw...
當她們問我看到什麼
...I can be very generous...
我可以很大方
...or very stingy.
也可以很小氣
Go on.
說下去
I can make you a legend.
我可以讓你成為傳奇
I can make you this generation's Milton Berle.
我可以讓你成為現代唐璜
-And Milton Berle has -Not compared to you.
而唐璜… 根本比不上你
They're not even touching the lasagna.
怎樣？ 客人碰都沒碰千層面
They love your casserole!
真的？ 他們好喜歡你的砂鍋
It's hard to believe a while ago this was just ingredients.
漂亮 不久前這些都還是材料呢
Everyone seems to like your dish.
大家都很喜歡你做的菜
And you?
那你呢？
I thought it was...
我覺得…
...quite tasty.
很好吃
So if everyone liked it, and you liked it...
要是大家都喜歡，你也喜歡
...that would make this a success. Which would make you....
那就代表很成功，而你就是…
A bitch?
惡婆娘？
I meant "wrong," but we can use your word.
我想說「你就錯了」 但你的說法也行
Yes,well,I was wrong.
對，我錯了
And I have to say...
我必須要說
...you really impressed me today.
你讓我大開眼界
You might even say that she "pulled a Monica."
你還可以說她搞了摩妮卡飛機
She doesn't know we switched it.
她不知道我們改過了
And the next time you cater for me...
下次你幫我辦外燴
...there will be nothing but ice in the freezer.
冷凍庫裡只會有冰
That really means a lot.
這是很大的鼓勵
Mom,don't bite your nails!
媽，別咬指甲
（中央咖啡館）
Hello,Chandler.
錢德你好啊
I love you.
我愛你
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
No,he doesn't!
少來了
Two hours,that lasted.
拖了2小時
So did you break up with Joanna?
所以你跟喬安娜分手了嗎？
I think so.
應該是吧
It's good you got out, before she blew up like Vesuvius.
幸好她跟維蘇威一樣爆炸之前 你就閃了
The volcano?
那座火山？
Speaking of volcanoes,man,are they a violent igneous rock formation!
對，講到火山 那些火成岩還真暴力
What?
什麼？
Lava spewing,hot ash.
熔岩亂噴，熱灰亂飛
Of course,some are dormant.
不過有些是休眠火山
Why are you talking about volcanoes all of a sudden?
你怎麼突然聊起火山來了？
We don't have to.
不一定要聊火山
What do you want to talk about? Vivisection?
你們想聊什麼？活體解剖？
The vas deferens?
輸精管？
The Vietnam War?
越戰？
Did anyone see that documentary on the Korean War?
有人看那部韓戰紀錄片嗎？
Korea's a beautiful country.
韓國那麼美
With such a sad history.
命運卻好悲慘
Could there be more Kims?
有好多姓金的
-Who's out there? -Me! Good morning!
外面是誰？ 是我，早安
Could you come in here,please?
瑞秋，你能不能進來一下？
Sure! They didn't have poppyseed bagels...
好 沒有罌粟籽焙果了
...so I have sesame Oh,my word!
所以我買芝麻…天哪
I've had a slight office mishap.
我出了一點辦公室災難
Could you get the key for me?
請把門後的鑰匙拿給我 好
-lf you could. -Oh,I'm sorry!
麻煩你 對不起
You can tell your friend Chandler we're definitely broken up this time!
告訴你的朋友錢德 我們這次絕對是分手了